Kevin Alford kevin.alford@pixelflow.org 904.571.7910 550 Lancaster St. #1 Jacksonville FL, 32204

Hello, my name is Kevin Alford, and I love creating things. Since a young age I have enjoyed programming, starting with QBASIC all the way up to my current love affair Ruby. I always try to stay on top of new techniques, whether its a better workflow, or new tools, I try to learn something new every day. I enjoy problem solving with others and sharing what I know. I try to stay involved in the ruby community by going to the RubyJax users group, as well as giving a hand helping others on the #railsbridge IRC room. I'm currently a Junior enrolled at University of North Florida taking my Bachelors in Computer Science, and have three years of professional Ruby on Rails experience. I am very comfortable with Test driven development, Pair Programming, editing in VIM, and managing applications with Ruby Version Manager and Bundler.

You can find me at:

- http://twitter.com/kevinalford
- http://blog.pixelflow.org
- http://github.com/zeroeth

Thank you for your consideration, Kevin Alford

Kevin Alford kevin.alford@pixelflow.org

Experience

Ruby on Rails

- Three years of professional experience.
- Complex RESTful systems combining forums, surveys, and reporting.
- Codes concise methods, well named methods and variables, using VIM
- Gem and plug-in authoring for reusable code.

Web Design

- Unobtrusive techniques, unit testing, event handling.
- Using Prototype/jQuery and interacting with json.
- Semantic html and css using 960grid, haml and sass for markup.
- Svg and canvas for interactive charts.

Testing

- Test driven development in Ruby using TestUnit, Shoulda, Cucumber.
- Using Factories and Integration tests.

Teamwork

- Comfortable with pair programming, always open to new ideas and criticism.
- Shared code ownership.
- Collaborates with others on code. (Frequents #rails and #railsbridge on IRC)

Java

- Desktop applications using Swing.
- Web applications using Java Server Pages and Faces.

Audio/Visual

- Recording and mixing sound for Jacksonville Symphony
- Camera operator for Dentist interviews.

Employment

- Bear Den Designs: Ruby on Rails Web Developer, A/V engineer. 2007-2011
- Alford Engineering: A2 Audio Engineer. 2003-Present
- Florida State College at Jacksonville Baymedows: Java Web Developer. 2007
- Brooks Rehabilitation: Computer Technician. 2007
- Sally Industries: Animatronics Animator/Programmer. 2005-2006
- Florida State College at Jacksonville Southside: Computer Technician. 2005
- Providence School: Computer Technician. 2004-2005

Education

- Florida State College at Jacksonville: Programming AS, General AA. 3.6 gpa 2005-2008
- University of North Florida: Junior (credits completed towards a BCS). 2010-Present

Interests

 Robotics, game programming, amateur radio, generative music, designing clocks, fractal world generation, photography. Kevin Alford <u>kevin.alford@pixelflow.org</u> 904.571.7910

References

- Marvin Thomas
 - o Florida State College: Java Developer, Co-worker
 - o mathomas@fccj.edu
 - o 904.997.2913 (Work)
 - o 904.548.0323 (Home)
- Amy Hisiger
 - Lutheran Medical Center Department of Dental Medicine: Long-Term Client, Friend
 - o <u>ahisiger@lmcmc.com</u>
 - o 718.630.6807 (Work)
- Dmitri Ratnikov
 - o Rails Developer, Google Java Developer, Friend
 - o ratnikov@gmail.com
 - o 312.560.2905 (Home)
- Steven DiFranco
 - o Florida State College: Python/Java/C Programming Professor
 - o sdifranc@fsci.edu
 - o 904.381.3592 (Work)
- Steve Phillips
 - Sally Industries: Co-worker
 - o 904.355.7100 (Work)